激动吧激动吧
Isn't this exciting?
只是个周末而已  老妈
It's just a weekend, mother.
爸  这是你与贝克特第一次共度浪漫周末
Dad, it's your first romantic weekend away with Beckett.
这可是大事
It's a big deal.
别给我压力  希望能成行吧
Okay, well, no pressure, and let's just hope it happens.
现在是四点半  如果到五点都没有凶案发生
4:30 now. If she doesn't catch a murder by 5:00,
那我们就能去了
We are in the clear.
说说看  有什么计划
So what do you have planned?
-我...什么意思  -你居然没计划
- I--what do you mean? - You don't have a plan?
-计划就是什么也不做  去放松  -理查德
- The plan is to do nothing, to relax. - Richard--
这可不是计划
That's not a plan.
女生不喜欢男生没计划
Women don't like it when men don't have a plan.
我现在上大学了  活在现实世界中
Hey, I'm in college now. I'm living in the world.
而且我看了很多杂志
Plus, I read a lot of magazines.
没有计划真的很糟糕
Not planning is really bad.
-好吧  -她说的对
- Okay-- - She's right.
如果有男人对我说  "晚餐去哪里吃"
A man says, "So what are we gonna do for dinner?"
切  果断不会有下文了
Pfft. He's dead to me.
好吧  我会在餐厅订位的
Okay. I will make reservations.
有浪漫情调的地方
Somewhere romantic.
-好的  -有档次的
- Right. - And classy,
因为凯特·贝克特是个有品位的女生
because Kate Beckett is a classy kind of gal, you know?
对
Right.
在星空下会很浪漫
Under the stars would be nice.
你知道在星空下还能做什么吗
Oh, and you know what else you can do under the stars--
好啦  不听不听不听
Okay. La la la la la la la
倒计时一分钟开始
T-minus one minute and counting.
卡塞尔  你来这里做什么
Castle, what are you doing here?
你应该在街角等我
You were supposed to wait around the corner
这样没人会看见
so that nobody'd see us.
我知道  但我觉得这样会很有意思
I know, but I thought it would be fun
在这里陪你看着时钟走到五点
to be here with you when the clock strikes 5:00.
就像过新年倒数一样
You know, just like new year's eve,
可惜不能亲吻  原因就不用多说了
except without the kissing for obvious reasons.
但这周末将会有无数的亲吻
But there will be plenty of that this weekend.
你小声点儿
Can you just shush?
没人会听到的
No one is going to hear me.
看看周围
Look around you.
满屋子的警探
You are in a room full of detectives...
完全没人发现蛛丝马迹
and not one of them has a clue.
卡塞尔
Wow, Castle.
多谢你提醒我
Thank you for reminding me that I'm lying
我在对很多自己关心的人撒谎
to a bunch of people that I really care about
这样才不会因为和你约会
so I don't get fired on an ethics violation
违反了职业操守而被炒鱿鱼
'cause I'm dating you.
你很快就会忘掉这些了  再过三
Well, you can put all that out of your mind in three...
二  一秒
two... one.
没有凶案
No murder.
怎样  有意思吧
There. Wasn't that fun?
好吧  我马上走  没人甚至会发现我来...
Okay, fine. I will go. And no one will even know I was--
卡塞尔
Hey, Castle.
你怎么来了  哥们儿
What you doing here, bro?
我正要去汉普顿
I was just on my way to the Hamptons
周末在那里写作
to write for the weekend,
我就想着顺路过来  看看有没有凶案发生
and--and I thought I'd drop by, see if we caught a murder.
哇  抓住一切机会逃避写作啊
Wow. Anything to avoid writing, huh?
-正是  -你听说了贝克特的周末计划吗
- Exactly. - Hey, did you hear about Beckett's weekend?
没有  有安排吗
No. Big plans?
她要和男朋友去度周末
She's going away with her boyfriend.
男朋友
A boyfriend?
贝克特  真的吗
Beckett! Really?
这个幸运的家伙是谁啊
Who is the lucky guy?
出于某些原因  她不说
For some reason, she's not telling.
各位  你们不是吧
Okay, seriously, guys?
事实上  我觉得被鄙视了
Actually, I for one am offended
你居然不告诉我们
that you're not sharing with us.
在我们同生共死那么多年后
After all we've been through.
就是  我们有知道真相的权利
Yeah, I think we deserve better.
知道吗  关于你们的权利
You know, I have a couple of ideas
我倒是有些不错的想法
about what you guys deserve.
拜托  贝克特  透露一下嘛
Come on, Beckett. Just give us something.
他长得帅吗
Is he handsome?
对  他帅吗
Yeah, I-is he handsome?
还是说他是个野性爷们
Or is he more of a badass?
是这样吗  贝克特  他是野性爷们吗
Yeah, is that it, Beckett? Is he, like, a bad boy?
像詹姆士·迪恩吗  他是亡命之徒吗
James Dean, huh? Is he a desperado?
我闪了
I'm gonna...
过来聊两句
Let me holla at you.
贝克特为什么要瞒着我们
Why would Beckett be holding out on us?
也许这男的有什么问题
Maybe there's something wrong with the guy.
也许是个麻烦鬼
Maybe he's bad news.
那么作为她的搭档
Well, then as her partners,
我们有责任调查出这男的是谁
it's our obligation to find out who this guy is.
如果不调查出来  我们还算什么搭档
And what kind of partners would we be if we didn't?
她的安全可能有危险
Her safety could be at stake.
正是  既然现在没有凶案要破
Exactly, and with no active murder case going on,
我们就用这段时间去调查吧
I say we use this time to find him.
到了
And here we are.
我的天  卡塞尔
Oh, my goodness, Castle.
哇
Wow.
看来...你是阔佬啊
So, um... are you rich or something?
没有詹姆斯·帕特森[惊悚小说大师]那么富有
Well, I'm not James Patterson rich,
不过还算有几个钱
but I do okay.
-来吧  带你参观下  -好的
- Come on. I'll show you around. - Yeah.
在重新装修厨房后
After I finished remodeling the kitchen,
我发誓我想收工了  但我的设计师打电话来
I swore I was done, but then my designer called.
她说客厅也要翻新
She said I had to tie in the living room,
我也照办了
so I did that, too.
接着就是二楼  然后是地下室
That led to the second floor, and then the basement.
来看看吗
You coming?
好的
Yeah.
这是我最喜欢的部分
This is actually my favorite part.
大海的波涛声  完全的私人空间
The sound of the ocean, complete privacy--
好平静
Oh, the serenity.
泳池在这边
The pool is right down here.
很多人觉得很吸引人
Most people find it magical.
你还好吗
Everything okay?
没事  这里...
Yeah. It's, um...
这里太壮观了  卡塞尔
It's spectacular, Castle.
这...不好吗
And is that a problem?
只是  我情不自禁会想
It's just, I can't help wondering
曾经有多少女人参观过这间房子
how many... other girls have gotten this tour.
对
Right.
我不会否认
Well, I'm not gonna deny
我曾经带其他女人来过这里
that I've brought other women up here.
但是
But, um...
她们都不是你
None of them were you.
你想  过去看下泳池吗
You want to, um, go and check out that pool?
要去吗
Yeah?
我敢肯定你会觉得水温很适宜
I'm sure you will find the temperature suitable...
但如果你想水温更高些
But if you would like it any warmer,
我可以调  或是我直接...
I can change the temperature or I could just...
闭嘴
Stop talking.
你忘了带泳衣
You forgot your suit.
我知道
I know.
怎么了
What?
有人过来了
Somebody's coming.
什么
What?
快报警
Call 9-1-1.
还要你说
Ya think?
他从海滩上跌跌撞撞地走过来
Yeah, he came stumbling up from the beach,
当时刚过10:15
Uh, just after 10:15.
他跌进了泳池  我想给他急救  但是...
Uh, collapsed into the pool. I tried to revive him, but--
你当时也在现场吗  女士
Were you here as well, ma'am?
是的
Yeah.
你的姓名是
Name, please.
凯瑟琳·贝克特
Um, Katherine Beckett,
但你能不能不要记录在案
But do you think we could keep that out of the public record?
当然
Of course.
不是说我们在做什么见不得人的事  只是
Not that we're doing anything wrong. I j--
明白
Right.
你这话是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
别担心  这里是汉普顿
Don't worry. It's the Hamptons.
我们会很谨慎的
We'll be discreet.
我们对你的"情趣安排"没有兴趣
We're--we're not interested in your arrangement.
-"情趣安排"  -警长
- Arrangement? - Chief, chief,
我  我不是  她不是...
Uh, I'm--I'm not-- I don't--she's not a--
我不是卖淫的
I'm not a prostitute.
那当然了
Oh, I'm sure.
那么  你对卡塞尔先生的陈述
So is there anything you'd like to add
有什么要补充的吗  女士
to Mr. Castle's statement, madam--ma'am?
是的
Yes.
我们并没有听到任何枪声
Only that we didn't hear any gunshots,
那很可能意味着凶手使用了消音器
So that probably means that the killer used a silencer.
平常没少看罪案剧吧
Watch a lot of cop shows, do we?
知道死者的身份了吗
Y-- uh, do we know who the victim is yet?
兰德尔·富兰克林
Uh, Randall Franklin.
他是从曼哈顿过来度周末的
He's a weekender, out here from Manhattan.
我们只知道  他今晚早些时候
All we know is that he was at a party up the beach
在道格拉斯·沙皮罗家的海滩上参加了派对
at Douglas Shapiro's house earlier this evening.
嘿  长官
Hey, chief!
我们抓到凶手了
We got him.
失陪
Excuse me.
我们抓到他了  他叫卡修斯·麦克莫瑞
We got him. Name is Casius Mcmurray.
本地的吸毒犯
Local meth user.
我们发现他
Found him asleep in the tall grass
在向东几百码的草丛中呼呼大睡
couple hundred yards to the east
他身上还藏有被害人的钱包
with the victim's wallet.
这货已经不省人事  嗑药嗑高了
Guy's out of it, high as a kite.
简直难以置信
That's unbelievable.
什么意思
What's that?
冰毒  那些富二代  什么都敢吸
Meth. These rich kids, they're into everything these days.
过去六个月  因吸毒被抓的数量已经翻倍了
Drug arrests have doubled in the last six months.
好吧  行了
Okay. Well...
谢谢你们的协助
Thanks for your help.
那血迹呢
Uh, what about blood spatter?
你们在海滩或是嫌疑人身上有发现血迹吗
Did you find any on the beach or on the suspect?
没  但还有必要找吗
No. But w-why would I even look?
我是说  我们已经抓到案犯了
I mean, we got the guy.
是啊  我相信一定会发现的
Yeah, I-I'm sure we will.
他身上有被害人的钱包
He had the victim's wallet.
是啊
Right.
话说  他可能是在沙滩上无意捡到那个钱包的
Y-you know, he could've found that wallet on the beach.
你是在质疑我的判断吗  卡塞尔先生
Are you questioning my judgment, Mr. Castle?
我
I...
-我觉得已经抓到案犯了  -好吧
- Think we got the guy. - Right.
-晚安  -晚安
- Good night. - Good night.
好了  走吧
All right. Come on. Let's go.
快点
Move.
什么样的冷血杀手
What kind of cold-blooded killer
会在射杀人之后还在沙滩上呼呼大睡
takes a nap on the beach after shooting someone?
卡塞尔  我是来度假的
Castle, I'm on vacation.
如果我想调查凶杀案
If I wanted to investigate a murder,
我直接留在市里就好了
I would've stayed in the city.
那家伙死在我的后院里
The guy died in my backyard.
这不是我们的案子
It's not our case.
但你必须承认  就案子来说
Still, you have to admit, as cases go,
此案实在弱爆了
it's pretty weak.
那也不是我们的案子  如果你继续纠结于此
It's still not our case, and if you keep obsessing over this,
会毁了我们的周末的
It's gonna ruin the weekend.
那我们该怎么做
So what do we do?
或许我们该试着不去想这件事
Maybe we just try putting it out of our minds, hmm?
好吧  但枪又是怎么回事
Yeah, but what about the gun?
他们应该在他身上找到枪才对的
They would've found the gun on him.
卡塞尔  你这可不叫不去想它
Castle, that's not putting it out of your mind.
你说得对  不好意思  我在纠结
You're right. I'm sorry. I'm obsessing.
-我不会再纠结了  -好的
- I won't obsess. - Okay.
但是你自己也说了没有听到枪声
Except you said it yourself about not hearing the shots.
什么样的吸毒犯
What kind of meth head
吸得都晕头转向  不知所以了
who obviously doesn't know what planet he's on
竟然会携带一把装有消音器的枪
carries a gun with a silencer?
那表明  他可是预谋作案啊
Which, by the way, indicates premeditation.
看来我们是没法好好度周末了
We're not gonna get on with our weekend
除非你找到答案  是吧
until you've gotten some answers, are we?
我去煮咖啡
I'll get the coffee.
好的  谢谢  道格
All right, thank you, Dougie.
我很遗憾错过了你的派对
And I'm sorry I missed the party.
我听说棒极了[杀手]
I heard it was killer.
抱歉  说错话了  明白
Yeah, sorry. Gotcha.
听好了  沙皮罗最后一次见到活着的富兰克林
Okay, last time Shapiro saw Franklin alive
是8:15分时在他的派对上
was at his party at 8:15.
就是他被杀前2小时
That's two hours before he was killed.
是的  他当时在海滩上
Right. He was on the beach
跟一个穿着白裙子的女人发生争吵
having an argument with a woman in a white dress,
但由于当时天很黑
But because it was already dark,
沙皮罗没认出那女人是谁
Shapiro couldn't tell who it was.
他知道那不是富兰克林的妻子
He knew it wasn't Franklin's wife,
因为她当时还在市里
because she was still back in the city.
你查到任何
Any luck finding a reason
令人想置富兰克林于死地的动机吗
why someone would want franklin dead?
实际上  他曾是雷曼兄弟公司的财务顾问
As a matter of fact, he was a banker at Lehman Brothers...
而且他曾在雷曼兄弟破产之前
And he was involved in an insider trading scandal
卷入内线交易丑闻
before they went belly up.
他为求自保  作证出卖同事
He cut a deal for his freedom by testifying against his colleagues.
蕾切尔·罗森博格  杰夫·福辛
Rachel Rosenberg, Jeff Forshim,
艾米丽·门罗  安琪拉·克拉伯  阿伦·勒纳
Emily Monroe, Angela Colabro, and Aaron Lerner.
他们都坐了牢  但现在都放出来了
Well, they all did time, but now that they're out,
他们当中的任何一个人都有可能复仇
Any one of 'em could have wanted revenge.
那三个女人中的一个可能就是白衣女人
And three of them could've been our mystery woman.
我们要去找富兰克林的妻子谈谈
We need to talk to Franklin's wife,
看看他有没有仇家
find out if he had any enemies.
不
No.
我们才刚到这儿  我才不要回市里呢
We just got here. I am not going back to the city.
幸运的是  我们不必回去
Well, fortunately, we don't have to.
我知道该打电话找谁
I know just who to call.
贝克特的男友
Beckett's boyfriend?
你们没有其他事可做了吗
Don't you two have something better to do?
实际上  真没有
Actually, no.
我们推测贝克特肯定是
We figure Beckett must have
在停职期间和那家伙勾搭上的
started up with the guy during her suspension.
那段时间她比较多愁善感
Pretty emotional time for her.
肯定需要一个男人的肩膀去依靠
I bet she needed a shoulder to lean on.
一个前任
An ex.
所以她才觉得很尴尬  不好意思告诉我们
It would explain why she's too embarrassed to tell us who it is.
那会让她显得很懦弱
It makes her look weak.
我们推测最可能的情况是
We're thinking the most likely scenario
她最近才分手的前一任
is that it was the last guy that she was with.
乔舒亚·戴维森医生
Dr. Joshua Davidson.
就是他  不是吗
It's him, isn't it?
好吧  我明白你生活空虚  哈维
Okay, I get that you don't have a life, Javi,
但你都结婚了  凯文  你又为何管闲事
But you're married, Kevin, so what's your excuse?
-我  -不管贝克特的男友是谁
- I-- - whoever Beckett's boyfriend is
都不关你们的事
is none of your business.
拜托  蕾妮  你肯定知道是谁
Come on, Lanie. You must know who it is.
她重回乔什的怀抱了  是吧
She went back to Josh, didn't she?
你就是这样审问犯人的吗
Is this how you interrogate people?
你这样什么都问不出来  只会把我惹得火大
'cause you ain't doing nothing but pissing me off.
我不知道那人是谁  而且我尊重贝克特的隐私
Now I don't know who it is, and I respect Beckett's privacy,
但我知道肯定不是乔什
but I do know it's not Josh
因为他从去年就一直在亚马逊河域
because he's been in the Amazon setting up free clinics
建免费诊所
for the last year.
你确定吗
Are you sure about that?
-我想她很确定  -是的
- I think she's sure. - Yeah.
卡塞尔
Hey, Castle.
我开扬声器
Yeah, I'm gonna put you on speakerphone
好让你也一起来讨论下
so you can weigh in on this.
讨论什么
Weigh in on what?
我们在太平间  和蕾妮一起
Well, we're in the morgue with Lanie
想找出谁是贝克特的男朋友
trying to figure out who Beckett's boyfriend is.
我和这些废话没一点关系
I have nothing to do with this nonsense.
没错  等贝克特发现了
Yeah, until you're
你就该为他们的碎尸装袋了
bagging their mangled bodies when Beckett finds out.
说得我们好像怕贝克特一样
Pfft. Like we're afraid of Beckett.
再说了  她怎么会知道
Besides, how's she gonna find out?
总之  我需要你们的帮助
Anyway, I need your guys' help.
在汉普顿  我家后院里发生了一起谋杀案
There has been a homicide out here in the Hamptons in my backyard.
真的假的  卡塞尔
Seriously, Castle?
你难道在拍《女作家与谋杀案》吗
What, are you in-- in an episode of "Murder, she wrote"?
更像《男作家与谋杀案》  但不幸的是
More like "Murder, he wrote," but unfortunately,
不像杰西卡·弗莱彻
unlike Jessica Fletcher,
当地警长可不是我的朋友
the local police chief-- not a friend of mine,
而且我觉得他很可能抓错人了  所以
and I think he may have the wrong guy, so...
我需要你们在城里审问被害人的妻子
I need you guys to question the victim's wife in the city,
看看她知道些什么
find out what she knows.
这可是很大一个忙啊  卡塞尔
Mm. That's a pretty big favor to ask, Castle.
我们需要点回报
We're gonna need something in return.
-法拉利车  -借一周  -每人一周
- The Ferrari. - For a week. - Each.
没搞错吧  伙计们
Seriously? Guys.
伙计们
Guys.
我不明白
I don't understand.
他们已经抓住凶手了  不是吗
They already caught the guy, didn't they?
警方告诉我  他是个瘾君子
I'm told he was some kind of drug addict.
出于对汉普顿警局的尊重
Well, with all due respect to the Hamptons P.D.,
我们想确保万无一失
we would like to make absolutely sure.
我们知道你丈夫
We know your husband
指证了几个雷曼兄弟公司的同事
testified against several colleagues at Lehman.
他和其中的谁还有联系吗
Has he been in contact with any of 'em?
为什么这么问
Why are you asking?
也许是他们中的某人找他报仇了
Maybe one of them came after him for revenge.
没有
No.
破产之后他就离开了银行业  再没回头
He left banking after the crash and never looked back.
转而投身了商业地产
Got into commercial real estate.
这样我们才得以生存下来
That's how we managed to stay afloat.
富兰克林夫人
Mrs. Franklin,
在你丈夫被杀前几小时  有人目击到
your husband was seen arguing with a woman on a beach
他和一个女人发生了争执
a couple of hours before he was killed.
你知道她会是谁吗
Do you have any idea who it could have been?
不知道
No.
但如果要我猜
But if I were to guess,
可能是他的女朋友
I'd say it was his girlfriend.
女朋友
Girlfriend?
他有外遇
He was having an affair?
某个叫娜塔莉娅·罗斯福的女人
With a Natalia Roosevelt.
她是当地人
She's a local.
妻子知道后  要他来这里和她分手
The wife got wind of it, sent him up here to break it off.
这可能是烂俗的汉普顿经典桥段
It's probably your typical tawdry Hamptons story.
外出度周末  遇见当地美女
Weekender meets local beauty,
减轻城市生活压力的灵丹妙药
the elixir to his stressful city life.
接着便是闪电般坠入爱河...
Whirlwind romance ensues...
但接着妻子发现了
But then the wife gets wind of it,
要他结束这段关系
forces him to end it,
这时灵丹妙药反倒成了毒药
and that's when the elixir becomes a poison...
用一把枪  只是...
with a gun, only...
结尾部分我还得想想
I'm gonna have to work on that last part.
不  故事不错  但我们要如何证明
No, it's a great story, but how do we prove
就是她在沙滩上和他发生争执的呢
that it was her that he was arguing with on the beach?
首先得查出
Well, the first step is to determine
当时她是否在派对上
whether she was at the party.
我来查下网上邀请
I'll check the e-vite.
娜塔莉娅·罗斯福  她在这里  在"参加"一列
And there she is-- Natalia Roosevelt... in the "Yes" column.
真是典型的蛇蝎美女啊
And, ooh, looking every bit the femme fatale.
卡塞尔  她曾是一名汉普顿的女议员
Castle, she was a Hamptons town councilwoman
也是汉普顿沙滩酒吧的老板
and the owner of the Hamptons sand bar.
那可是当地著名的酒吧
That is a popular local watering hole.
我能请你喝杯酒吗
Can I buy you a drink?
她在那儿
There she is...
我们要找的白裙女子
our lady in the white dress.
只是现在她衣着血红  令人炫目
Only now she's looking dazzling in blood red.
有什么计划
So what's our play?
低调点  卡塞尔
Just keep it light, Castle.
自然地过渡到谋杀案上
Find a natural way of bringing up the murder.
看她作何反应
See how she reacts.
我知道该做什么
I know just what to do.
我认得你
Hey, I recognize you.
你昨晚在道格拉斯·沙皮罗的派对上
You were at Douglas Shapiro's party last night.
谁不在呢
Ah, who wasn't?
是吗  但我又看见你在沙滩上
Right? But I saw you on the beach.
那时你不是在和兰德尔·富兰克林起争执吗
Weren't you arguing with Randall Franklin?
低调  卡塞尔  我说要低调
Light, Castle. I said light.
你在暗示什么
What are you implying?
没什么  只是在想你一定觉得怪怪的
Nothing, no. Only it must be weird for you.
毕竟你是最后一个见到他还活着的人
You had to be the last person to see him alive.
警长
Hey, uh, chief.
是的  娜塔莉娅
Yeah, Natalia.
-过来  -糟糕
- Come here. - Oops.
你认识这两个人吗
Do you know these guys?
因为他们基本是在指控我谋杀了
Because they are practically accusing me of murder.
卡塞尔  你在这里做什么
Castle, what are you doing here?
就聊聊天
Uh, just having a conversation.
聊富兰克林的谋杀案
About Franklin's murder?
你对我办案的方法有意见吗
Hey, you got a problem with the way I do my job?
我绝不会那样说的
Uh-- now I would never use those words exactly.
是吗  那这句如何
Oh, well, how about these words?
你和你的妓女朋友
You and your hooker friend are under arrest
因涉嫌妨碍凶案调查而被捕了
for interfering with my murder investigation.
转过去
Turn around.
多谢你的酒
Thanks for the drink.
干杯
Cheers.
真不敢相信我竟然被你说服
I cannot believe I let you talk me into
干涉了另一个警局的凶案调查
getting involved in another department's murder investigation.
说得好像我强迫你一样
Oh, like I needed to twist your arm.
至少我们对这家伙的看法是正确的
And at least we know we were right about this guy.
你觉得他看起来像是有负罪感的样子吗
I mean, does he look like he has a guilty conscience to you?
他睡得像个婴儿一样香
He's sleeping like a little baby.
更像是个小声的电锯
More like a baby chainsaw.
卡塞尔  贝克特  布雷迪警长想见你们
Castle, Beckett, Chief Brady wants to see you.
警长
Chief.
谢了  琼斯
Hey, thanks, Jones.
你们好  伙计们
Hi, guys.
要来点咖啡吗  刚泡的
You want some coffee? It's fresh.
好的  谢谢
Yeah, thanks.
我谷歌过你了  贝克特女士
So I googled you, Ms. Beckett.
我不知道你是名凶案科警探
I didn't realize you were a homicide detective.
我之前从没真正碰到过谋杀案
I've never actually worked a homicide before.
除了逮捕毒贩  我处理的大部分案子都是
Other than drug arrests, I deal mostly with folks
人们抱怨邻居家的狗在他们的花园里拉屎
complaining about their neighbor's dog pooping in their garden.
我甚至连枪都没掏过
I've never even pulled my gun.
对不起
I'm sorry.
为什么要跟我们说这些
Uh, why are you telling us this?
关于那个嗑药的人  你说对了
Because you were right about the meth addict.
化验结果显示他手上没有射击后的残留物
The lab results came back negative for gunshot residue,
也就是说真正的凶手仍然在逃
which means that the killer is still at large.
市长给了我很大压力
Look... I'm getting a lot of pressure from the mayor.
有钱的游客被谋杀了
Rich weekender getting murdered,
这对我们的旅游业可不好
not exactly good for business.
我还是不明白你跟我们说这些干嘛
Still not getting why you're telling us this.
直说了吧
Okay.
如果你们帮我调查这起谋杀
I will drop the interference charge
我就不再起诉你们干涉我查案
if you help out with the investigation.
我可以接受
Sounds good to me.
失陪一会
Excuse me for a second.
可以接受
Sounds good?
我们刚刚在拘留室度过了两个小时的假期时光
We just spent two hours of our vacation in lockup.
你还嫌不够吗
Isn't that enough?
你真的觉得
Well, do you really think
我们不抓到凶手  不把他绳之以法
we'll be able to relax without getting any answers...
还能享受这个假期吗
without... getting justice?
好吧
Fine.
只要不让我辖区的人知道  我就帮你
As long as word doesn't get back to my precinct that I'm doing this.
没问题
Works for me.
那么我们下一步该做什么
So what do we do next?
弹道分析结果出来了吗
Did you get ballistics back?
出来了
Oh, yes. Uh...
上面说
Let's see.
死者体内的子弹口径是30毫米
Bullets pulled from the victim were 30 caliber.
30毫米  这种子弹很少见啊
30 caliber. Those are pretty rare, aren't they?
对  一般用于打猎
Yeah, that's usually used for hunting small game.
我能看一下法医对富兰克林做的尸检报告吗
Can I see the M.E.'s report on Franklin's body?
报告还没来
It has not come in yet.
那我建议你去催一下法医让他快点
Then I suggest you pressure the M.E. to get it back.
与此同时
In the meantime,
我们应该审问一下娜塔莉娅·罗斯福
we should interrogate Natalia Roosevelt.
我已经盘问过她了
Oh, I already spoke to her.
她没有杀富兰克林的动机
She has no motive for killing Franklin.
你问过她当富兰克林情妇的事了吗
And did you ask her about being his mistress?
没有
No.
她没跟我说这事啊
She didn't mention that.
是啊
Yeah.
嫌疑人一般不会主动说这些事的
Suspects tend to hold back on stuff like that.
真有乡村风味
Flavor country.
我还以为你把他们抓起来了呢  约翰
I thought you arrested these guys, John.
这位是
Um, that's--
你应该称他布雷迪警长  罗斯福小姐
That's Chief Brady to you, Ms. Roosevelt,
你还是担心一下你自己
And shouldn't you be more concerned about the fact that
在跟兰德尔·富兰克林有染的事上撒了谎吧
you lied to him about your affair with Randall Franklin?
我没有撒谎
I didn't lie to him.
布雷迪警长从没问过我这件事
Chief Brady never asked me about it.
昨晚在海滩上兰德尔是不是要跟你分手
Didn't Randall break up with you on the beach last night?
是又怎么样
So what if he did?
那你就有杀人动机了  罗斯福小姐
So that gives you motive, Ms. Roosevelt.
听我说  我并不否认
Look... I am not denying
我当时跟兰德尔起了争执
that I was fighting with Randall.
我指责他
I accused him of...
利用我来获得委员会的投票
using me to get my council vote.
关于什么的投票
Your vote on what?
他那宝贝的直升机降落场
His beloved helipad.
六个月前他在自家后院建起来的
He put the thing in his backyard six months ago.
但是他想要做些变动
But he needed a variance.
我们上周批准同意了
We approved it last week.
之后  他就把我甩了
Next thing you know, he dumps me.
两个小时后他就被枪杀了
Then he was shot and killed two hours later.
那个时候我已经回到我的酒吧了
Two hours later, I was back at my bar.
我最后看见他是在海滩上
Look, the last time I saw him was on that beach.
当时我们正在争吵  他突然接到一条短信
We were still arguing when he got a text
然后就立马闪人了
and he suddenly ran off.
那时候是几点
And what time was that?
大约八点半
About 8:30.
他往哪去了
Which way did he go?
往海滩上方
Up the beach.
先到这吧
Okay, then.
我查到了富兰克林离开罗斯福小姐前
So I tracked down that text that Franklin got
在海滩上收到的那条短信
before leaving Ms. Roosevelt on the beach.
看不到短信的内容
Couldn't get the content,
但是能确定是发自一部一次性手机
But it was sent from a burner phone.
发信息的人不想暴露身份
Whoever sent it wished to remain anonymous.
可能是关于一些糟糕的生意
Maybe it was about bad business deals.
之前他们就是因为那些生意才陷入困境的
That's what got him in trouble with his colleagues in the past.
他的过去还真是阴魂不散啊
The past does have a funny way of repeating itself.
说到这个
Speaking of which,
我给盗窃组的熟人打了电话
I have calls into my sources at robbery
想看看贝克特是不是和老情人
to try to link Beckett to her old beau--
戴明探长有联系
Detective Demming.
戴明  别逗了
Demming? Come on.
贝克特能找到比他好得多的
Beckett could do so much better.
谢谢你们的汇报  我得挂了
Uh, thank you for the update. I gotta go.
你为什么要帮他们呢
Why are you even helping them?
好消息是
Well, come on. The good news is,
他们完完全全地被我们骗了
they're completely fooled about us.
我都不理解他们为什么那么八卦
Yeah, well, I don't understand why they even care.
是啊  为什么人们喜欢八卦布拉吉丽娜呢
Ah, why do people care about Brangelina?
我们现在成了布拉吉丽娜了
Oh, so we're brangelina now?
不不不  我们是理凯特
No. No, no. We're... Rickate.
不好  我们是  凯特克
No, we're... Kate-ick.
卡塞克特
Cas-kett?
这个好  凶杀案总是和棺材有关
Ooh, that's good 'cause of the whole murder thing--casket.
娜塔莉娅·罗斯福的不在场证据很充分
So Natalia Roosevelt has a solid alibi.
她酒吧的三个老顾客确认了昨晚九点的时候
Three patrons of her bar confirmed she was there
她在酒吧里
9:00 last night.
那时距离富兰克林被杀还有很长时间
Long before Franklin was shot.
我派琼斯副警长沿着海滩
I got deputy Jones canvassing the houses along the beach
挨家挨户排查  就是富兰克林离开的那个方向
in the direction she said Franklin went.
只有琼斯副警长吗
Just deputy Jones?
这是汉普顿
It's the Hamptons.
我们没有太多的人手
We don't have a lot of resources.
对了  你们不是想看这个吗
Oh, by the way. I know you wanted to see this.
法医的尸检报告
It's the M.E. report.
富兰克林的肺里充满了海水
Uh, Franklin's lungs were full of saltwater.
这意味着他差点淹死  这就怪了
Meaning he almost drowned. That's strange.
还有  根据他枪伤的情况来看
And based on the condition of the gunshot wounds,
他在被击中后至少泡在海里20分钟
he was in the ocean at least 20 minutes after being shot.
好的  这样的话
Okay, so...
在海里泡了20分钟
In the ocean for 20 minutes,
没人听到枪声
no one heard the shots being...
这就是没人听到枪声的原因
that's why no one heard the shots.
他被射击后掉下了船  《教父》风格
He was shot off a boat, "Godfather" Style.
海水减缓了他的出血量
And the saltwater slowed down his bleeding,
使他有足够的时间游上岸
giving him enough time to make it to shore.
那么  我们是不是应该去查查
So what, we should try and figure out
案发时哪些船在那附近
which boats were in the vicinity at that time?
是的
Yeah. So...
我们有没有证人昨晚在海滩上呢
Do we have a witness who we know was on the beach last night?
你是说
You mean someone like...
咱们的嗑药睡婴
our favorite meth addict--
麦克莫瑞
Mcmurray?!
没搞错吧
Seriously?
那伙当时都嗨翻了
The guy was whacked out on meth.
是的  但这并不意味着他忘了他所看见的事
Yeah, but that doesn't mean that he doesn't remember what he saw.
是的  我看到了一艘船
Yeah, I saw a boat...
距离海岸大约100码
About 100 yards off the beach.
很好  你能描述一下船的样子吗
Okay, great. Can you describe it?
比如大小
Maybe it's size.
记不得了  我只记着那船当时正受到攻击
Nah. All I remember is, it was being attacked.
攻击
Attacked?
对  鲨鱼袭击
Yeah, by a shark.
一条红眼睛的红色鲨鱼
A red shark with red eyes.
好吧  也许你说的没错
Okay, maybe you are right about him.
也不一定
Maybe not.
对  我知道那船  就在那里
Yeah, I know that boat. It's just this way.
船主叫阿伦·勒纳
Owned by Aaron Lerner.
阿伦·勒纳
Aaron Lerner.
那是被富兰克林送入监狱的其中一个
That's one of the guys Franklin sent to prison.
你是否知道那船昨晚有没有出航
Do you know if that boat went out last night?
是  大概九点半左右我看见它离开
Yeah, I saw it pull away around 9:30.
那是富兰克林在海边
That's an hour after
离开娜塔莉娅·罗斯福的一小时以后
Franklin left Natalia Roosevelt on the beach.
他有足够的时间赶到这里
That's plenty of time for him to get here.
如果船是在九点半起航
If the boat left here by 9:30,
那他就能轻松地在9:45掉进我家的游泳池
it could've easily made it to the water off my house by 9:45.
红色鲨鱼
Red shark.
鲨鱼袭击
Shark attack.
小心脚下
Oh, watch your step. Ohh!
该死的周末船客
Damneded weekend boater.
卡塞尔  溅落的血迹
Castle... Blood spatter.
富兰克林就是在这里中枪的
Franklin was shot right there.
好啊  勒纳
Hey, Lerner.
凶手之船[双关: 船真赞]
Killer boat.
这是对我们在甲板上找到的
It's the lab report on the blood splatter
血迹的检验报告  勒纳先生
we found on the deck, Mr. Lerner.
与兰德尔·富兰克林的血样相同
It's a match to Randall Franklin.
也就是说他是在你船上中枪的
Meaning he was shot on your boat.
不  不可能  他根本就没上船
No, that's not possible. He wasn't even on it.
那血迹是哪来的
How did it get there?
我也不知道
I have no idea.
我们有证人看到你的船
We have a witness who saw your boat
于昨晚9:30离开码头
leaving the marina at 9:30 last night.
你去哪里了
Where did you go?
我昨晚没有开船
I didn't take it out last night.
得了吧  勒纳
Lerner, come on.
我们都知道兰德尔·富兰克林也跟你一样犯了法
We know Randall Franklin was guilty of breaking
但就因为他出卖了你
all the same laws you broke, but he got off scot-free
却被无罪释放
because he ratted you out.
你要给他点教训也是可以理解的
It's understandable you'd want a little payback.
等等  没错  当然  我的确很愤怒
Wait. All right. Sure. Yeah, I held a grudge.
谁不会呢  但你们知道吗
Who wouldn't? But you know something?
几个月前  我在海边碰到他
I met him on the beach a few months ago,
我们和解了
and we buried the hatchet.
我甚至还去他家吃过几次饭
I've even had dinner at his house a couple times.
那昨晚八点半到十点之间你到底在哪儿
And exactly where were you 8:30 and 10:00 last night?
互助组
Group.
减肥互助组  怎么了
W--a weight-loss group at the rec. What?
听着  你们要想抓住杀害他的真凶
Look, you want to catch the guy who actually killed him,
就该去查查他的邻居
check out his neighbor.
你说什么  他的邻居
I'm sorry. His neighbor?
没错  那是个可怕的混蛋
Oh, yeah. This guy's a scary bastard.
上个礼拜  我在富兰克林家吃饭
I'm having dinner at Franklin's a week ago, right?
他邻居来了  死命地敲着大门
Neighbor comes over, starts banging on the front door.
富兰克林也不肯告诉我是怎么回事
Franklin wouldn't tell me what it was about,
不过那家伙是各种恐吓他
but this guy was threatening him with all kinds of violence.
好吧  谢谢
Okay, thanks.
好了  勒纳的不在场证明成立
Well... Lerner's alibi checks out.
他昨晚八点半到十点一直在减肥互助组
He was at the weight-loss group from 8:30 to 10:00 last night.
也就是说有人开走了他的船
Meaning someone else took out his boat,
杀了富兰克林
killed Franklin,
在勒纳不知晓的情况下又把船开了回来
and then brought it back without Lerner... Learning.
我叫琼斯再仔细查查码头
I'll have Jones canvass the marina.
我们知道邻居是谁吗
Meantime, do we know who this neighbor is?
知道  就是点财产纠纷
Yeah. It's just a property dispute.
在这里很常见
They're a dime a dozen around here.
是啊  不过听勒纳的描述
Yeah, but the way that Lerner describes it,
事情似乎挺严重的
it sounded like it was something pretty heated.
那邻居的脾气确实有点火爆
Well, the neighbor's a bit of a hothead,
但我告诉你
but, um, I'm telling you,
那不是谋杀的动机
it is not a motive for murder.
我们至少应该找这个人谈谈吧
Shouldn't we at least talk to this guy?
听好了  他可不是什么一般人
Okay, look, it's not just any guy.
他是文森特·卡达诺
It's vincent Cardano.
卡达诺罪案家族的"疤头"文尼吗
Vinnie "The scar" of the Cardano crime family?
怪不得这船上枪杀的行径这么"教父"式
That would explain the "Godfather" style of the boat shooting.
我是他堂弟萨尔的朋友
I'm friends with his cousin Sal.
他一直想介绍我们认识来着
He's been trying to get us together for years.
此时不去更待何时
And what better time than the present?
我们可以把他带来问问他昨晚干了什么
We could bring him over and ask him what he did last night.
不  不行
Whoa. Okay. No.
我不能凭白无故叫卡达诺来
I am not going at Cardano without proof.
我得走了
Look, I gotta run.
我得去给汉普顿桥杯
I gotta go reroute traffic
水球半决赛管管秩序
for the Bridgehamptons polo semifinals.
不过记住
But remember--
我们晚点再解决这事
We'll finish this later.
这里我说了算
I call the shots.
不许私自联系疤头文尼
No contacting Vinnie the scar.
真开心我们终于见面了  里奇  干杯
I'm glad we could finally get together, Ricky. Salud.
萨尔肯定跟你说过我是你超级粉丝
I'm sure that Sal told you I'm a big fan of your work.
-敬新朋友  -干杯
- So to new friends. - Yes. Hear, hear. Cheers.
亲爱的  这肉酱真是美味至极
Ah, sweetie. This meat sauce is to die for.
谢谢  文尼
Thank you, Vinnie.
没错  这是棒极了  我不知道你居然还会做饭
Actually, it is excellent. I didn't know you could cook.
你该多留心  卡塞尔
You should pay a little more attention, Castle.
看见了吧  这就是我和卡塞尔的区别
Ooh, see, that's the difference between Castle and me.
亲爱的  自从我来到这里
You've had my complete attention
你就抓住了我所有的注意力
since I've been here, sweetheart.
小心着点  文尼
Whoa, whoa. Watch it, Vinnie.
别逼着我做出像某人对你邻居做的事
Don't make me have to do to you what someone did your neighbor.
你也听说了吧
Oh, you heard about that, huh?
听说  那人就是死在我游泳池的
Heard about it? The guy ended up in my pool.
是啊  我得承认
Yeah. Well, you know, I gotta admit,
我可不会为他掉一滴眼泪
I'm not gonna shed any tears over that guy.
你认识他吗
Oh, so you knew him, huh?
那家伙是个混蛋
Ah, the guy was a real bastard.
他在他的花园里造了个直升机场地
Uh, he builds a helicopter pad in his yard
离我家都不到50英尺
not 50 feet from my house.
每周二半夜
Every Tuesday around midnight,
他都会轰隆隆地飞过我的卧室
he buzzes right past my bedroom.
真是混球
The balls on that guy.
是啊  所以我去投诉
Yeah, so--so I complain,
但市政会不管  他们批准的
but the town council, they approve it anyway.
我就知道他肯定给了他们好处
I know for a fact that guy greased palms.
真想杀了他
Oh-ho, I wanted to kill him.
我想也是
I bet.
得知他的死讯时你在哪儿
So where were you when you found out about it?
不知道  怎么了
I don't know. What's it matter?
你说  你想他死的人真死了
Well, it's just, a guy you wanted killed ends up killed?
这事能有多大概率
How often does that happen?
不知道
I don't know.
你想说什么  卡塞尔
What are you saying, Castle?
你以为是我杀了他
You think I killed the guy?
不  文尼  没有  我们就随便聊聊
Well, n-no. Vinnie, no. We're just talking here.
不  请坐  再来点酒吗
No, sit down. Have some more wine.
不  我们吃完了
No, we're finished here.
坦白说  我很生气
And frankly, I am offended that you think
你居然会以为我会做出这么外行的事
I would do such a bush-league hit.
如果我想灭了他
If I had whacked that guy,
谁也别想找到尸体
nobody'd ever find the body.
别逼我给你做个示范
Don't make me wanna do a demonstration.
他说的有道理
He makes a valid point.
尸体  瘾君子  还有黑帮家族
Dead bodies, meth heads, and mobsters--wow.
这就是你所谓的浪漫周末吗
Is that what you mean by a romantic weekend?
我是不是该提醒你一下
May I remind you that it was murder
当初我们就是通过凶杀案相识的
that brought us together in the first place?
你好
Hello.
我不是嘱咐过吗  卡塞尔
what did I tell you, Castle?
我说的清清楚楚  不要联系卡达诺
I was crystal clear. I said no contacting Cardano!
什么  我们就友好地吃了个饭而已
What? Oh, that was just a friendly meal.
而且  我们还剩了点意大利面
Actually, we have some linguine left
你可以过来一起啊
If you'd like to come over.
你们指控他谋杀
You accused him of murder!
而且他觉得是我让你们这么干的
And now he thinks I put you up to it.
好的一面是我们可以确定他不是疑犯
On the bright side, we can rule him out as a suspect.
他从来就是不是疑犯
He was never a suspect in the first place.
总而言之
Bottom line is,
凶手还逍遥法外
The killer's still out there.
别扯了  总而言之就是经过你们一折腾
No. No, no, no. The bottom line is that after what you just pulled,
我还是自己找凶手
I will find him myself,
不用你们帮忙了
without any more of your help.
听着  警长
Look, Chief--
要是我发现你们再碰这个案子  我发誓
And if I catch you guys anywhere near this case again, I swear...
我亲自把你们请出这里
I will out the two of you.
我猜他不过来吃面了呗
So I guess it's a "No" on the linguine.
嗯  他说他已经吃过了
No. He, uh... said he already ate.
走吧
Shall we?
我仔细查了查
Hey. So I took a closer look
兰德尔·富兰克林房地产投资
at Randall Franklin's real estate investments.
这家伙在萧条的社区里
The guy was buying up distressed properties
买下了一堆困厄房产并改造成公寓
in dying neighborhoods and turning 'em into condos.
听起来是个不错的投资啊
Sounds like smart investments.
是啊  但是他没有装修
Yeah, but he wasn't renovating 'em.
也没有出租  什么都没干
He wasn't leasing 'em out, nothing.
所以说他还在承担着按揭
So he was carrying the mortgage,
可是房子并没有盈利
but the buildings weren't throwing off any income?
他的妻子说
And his wife said that
房地产投资让他们狠赚了一笔
the real estate investments were keeping them flush.
这说不通啊
It doesn't add up.
对啊
You're right.
房子里一定有蹊跷
Has to be something going on in those buildings.
只有一个办法可以知道
Only one way to find out.
富兰克林绝对
ugh. Franklin definitely
一个子都没花在装修这鬼地方上
didn't put any money into renovating this dump.
这地方是废弃的
Place is deserted.
他绝对没在这儿赚到钱
He's definitely not making any money here.
-那到底从哪里赚的  -我也不知道
- Yeah, so where's it coming from? - I don't know.
不是吧
Really?
你现在看短信
You're checking your text messages right now?
贝克特的事  哥们儿
It's about Beckett, bro.
她没和戴明在一起
Ah! She's not with Demming.
劫案组的莫拉莱斯说他和一个副警探约会
Morales in robbery says that he's been dating a vice detective...
有四个月了
for the last four months.
听见了吗
You hear that?
听见了
Yeah.
我真不喜欢这事  哥们儿
I don't like this, bro.
我也一样
No, me neither.
我们不会敲门的
No way we're knocking on that door.
房子的主人死了
Okay. Well, the building owner's dead,
老婆也接受了调查  所以
and the wife is down with us investigating, so...
纽约警局
NYPD!
靠墙站  快点
Up against the wall right now! Move!
靠墙  靠墙
Move! Move! Move!
Move it! Move it! Move it!
看起来富兰克林找到
Looks like Franklin found a way
换钱的好方法了
to monetize his investment after all--
制造毒品
Making crank.
是啊  这绝对是个制毒厂
Yeah. This is definitely a meth lab.
所以说富兰克林是个毒品贩子
So Franklin was a meth kingpin, huh?
事实证明他所有的地产
Turns out, all of his properties
都有制毒厂
Housed meth labs,
不过这对一个以前制假帐的人来说
which makes sense for someone who...
是绝对说得通的
used to cook the books.
这就是他被杀的原因
That's why he was killed.
毕竟是个危险的行当
It's a dangerous business.
现在的工作可以交给纽约方面了
Well, it's all about New York now.
-他俩接手了  -对
- The boys can take it from here... - Yeah.
我们也可以继续这事找上我们之前
and we can pick up right where we left off
没干完的事了
before this whole thing came to us.
是啊  不过  为什么找上我们
Yeah, but... Why did it come to us?
这世界还挺幽默的  我觉得
Uh... The universe has a sense of humor, I suppose.
不不不  我是说如果和毒品有关
No, no, I mean, if this is about meth,
他为什么没在纽约被杀
then why wasn't he killed in New York?
没准凶手喜欢沙滩
Maybe the killer likes the beach.
不  我觉得这背后还有隐情  卡塞尔
No, I think there's gotta be more to it, Castle.
他们知道勒纳的船
I mean, they knew about Lerner's boat.
你猜怎么着  我觉得他们一定能查出来
You know what? I'm sure the boys will figure it out.
这就需要了解富兰克林的生活
And that requires an intimate knowledge about Franklin's life.
这是本地人知道的事
That's local knowledge.
对  对  对
Right, right, right.
没准杀手认真研究了
Well, maybe the killer just did his homework.
对  但是为什么他们要费那么大劲呢
Yeah, but why would they go to all of that trouble?
如果他是纽约的毒贩子
I mean, if he was a kingpin in New York city,
为什么他们在这里把他杀了
Why would they kill him out here?
除非有一部分的生意是在这里进行的
Unless part of the drug business was out here.
这就解释了直升机
That explains the helicopter.
他需要直升机把毒品转移这里
He needed the helicopter to transfer the drugs out here.
这就是他和娜塔莉娅鬼混  还贿赂她的原因
And why he slept with Natalia and greased palms.
他需要取得直升机场的使用批准
He needed approval to get the helipad.
是  用直升机转移毒品
Yes, much less risky to move your product in a helicopter
可比船和车安全多了
rather than boat or car.
没有警察会叫你停下来
No cop is gonna pull you over.
布雷迪警长说这里的毒品问题
You know, Chief Brady said that the drug problem
在过去六个月猛增了一倍
has doubled over the past six months.
而这正是富兰克林开始用直升机的时间
Exactly when Franklin started using his helicopter.
对不起  卡塞尔  我觉得你应该
I'm sorry, Castle. But I think you should probably...
给莱恩和埃斯波西托打电话了
Call Ryan and Esposito.
是啊
Yeah.
看来卡塞尔是对的
Looks like Castle was right.
直升机飞行安排
His helicopter's flight plans coincide
与制毒厂出货时间吻合
with when the shipments left the meth labs.
也与他邻居抱怨的
They also coincide with the late-night landings
夜晚降落时间吻合
that his neighbor was complaining about.
现在我们知道富兰克林转移毒品的原因了
So now we know how Franklin was moving his product.
但是还是没有告诉我们凶手是谁
But it still doesn't tell us who killed him.
或许能  你去哪里
Well, maybe it does, but where are you going?
见个以前的联调局的哥们儿
To meet an FBI buddy of mine
看看贝克特是不是和老情人索伦森复合了
to see if Beckett's back with her old flame Sorenson.
怎么了
Why?
周二的货单中
The flight manifest for Tuesday--
还顺道送了个客人
it includes a guest.
有人和他在一起
Someone else was with him.
好吧  我查索伦森  你查直升机小子
All right, I'm on sorenson. You go get helicopter boy.
我就坐了次富兰克林的直升机
So I got a ride on Franklin's helicopter.
怎么了
So what?
这也无法证明我的委托人一起运毒
That doesn't prove my client was trafficking drugs with him.
是  但是这些能证明
True. These do.
制毒厂工人的签字申请
Signed affidavits from the meth lab workers
说明你每周二都去提货  勒纳
that you picked up product every Tuesday, Lerner.
你从银行业转行到制毒业
You went from making bank to making crank.
我没杀富兰克林
I didn't kill Franklin.
而且布雷迪警长已经证实了我在汉普顿的
A-and Chief Brady already confirmed my alibi
不在场证明
In the Hamptons.
没准你雇凶杀人
Well, maybe you hired someone to kill him.
我觉得你一直对富兰克林怀恨在心
See, I think you never got over your grudge against Franklin.
我认为你和他合伙
I think that you partnered with him,
但你却一直打算将他赶走
but you always planned to knock him off
然后接手全部生意  我说得对吗
and take over the business. Am I getting close?
对  对  你说得很对  但是你搞错人了
Yeah, yeah, you're close, but you just got the wrong guy.
什么意思
What do you mean?
就在上周  富兰克林在抱怨一个当地人
Just last week, Franklin was complaining about a local.
当地毒贩吗
A local drug dealer?
没错  似乎他对我们抢他生意很不满意
Yes. Seems he didn't appreciate us moving in on his business.
谁  说出名字
Who? Give me a name.
我不知道名字
I don't know a name,
但是富兰克林很怕他
but Franklin seemed really spooked.
他还跟你说了什么
What else did he tell you about him?
我只知道这么多
That's all I know.
其他一切我都告诉了布雷迪和他的两个顾问
Everything else I told to Brady and his two consultants.
两个顾问
Two consultants?
是啊  那个作家卡塞尔和他的女朋友
Yeah, yeah, the writer Castle and his girlfriend.
女朋友  你说什么女朋友
Girlfriend? Wh-wh-what do you mean, girlfriend?
这很重要吗
What does that matter?
伙计  在这里只有我能问问题
Hey! Hey! I'll ask the questions here, pal.
你是说理查德·卡塞尔在审问时
Are you telling me that Richard Castle
带着他的女朋友吗
brought his girlfriend in your interrogation?
是啊
Yeah.
她叫什么
What was her name?
我不记得
I don't remember.
那描述一下
Well, then describe her.
勒纳  描述一下她  快点
Describe her, Lerner! Now!
好吧  高高的  中长发
Okay! Tall, uh, uh, medium length hair.
这是要干嘛
What's this about?
什么颜色  头发什么颜色
What color? G-give me a hair color.
棕色
Uh, uh, brown.
棕色  我想眼睛也是棕色  很漂亮
Brown. Brown eyes, too, I think. Really pretty.
体型呢
Body type?
棒极了  真的棒极了
Awesome. I mean, awesome.
她  苗条  美死了...  她很热辣
She was, like, thin, gorge-- she was hot.
非常热辣
She was really hot.
凯特
Kate!
名叫凯特
Name was Kate!
混...
Son of a...
你是对的  卡塞尔
You were right, Castle.
富兰克林利用自己的直升飞机
Franklin was using his helicopter
将毒品运到汉普顿
to move meth to the Hamptons.
看起来你让案子有了大进展
Looks like you blew this case wide open.
我想现在你又能重新专注写作了吧
Guess you can get back to your writing now, huh?
还是要找出到底凶手是谁
Well, there's still the matter of finding out who the killer is.
是的  我觉得布雷迪知道自己要做什么
Yeah, well, I think Brady knows what he has to do.
我已经告诉他去找一个当地毒贩
I already told him to look for a local drug dealer
会因富兰克林的扩张计划
who would've been feeling squeezed
受到排挤
by Franklin's expanding operation.
这个想法不错  干得漂亮
Well, that's a great theory. Nice work.
谢了  不过
Oh, thanks, but, uh,
这不是我的理论
it's not my theory.
今天早上我审讯
Aaron Lerner gave it up
阿伦·勒纳的时候  他提出的
when I interrogated him this morning.
阿伦·勒纳
Aaron lerner? Aar--uh...
你也审讯过阿伦·勒纳了
So you interrogated Aaron Lerner, too?
是的  他回来了
Yeah, he's back in the city.
而且他还是富兰克林的犯罪同伙
Turns out he was Franklin's partner in crime.
你了解了什么
Wow. What do you know?
卡塞尔  不好了
Castle, not good.
知道  别紧张
I know. Relax.
-别紧张  -我怎么能不紧张
- Relax? - How can I relax?
卡塞尔  你在听吗
You still there, Castle?
在的  还在
Yeah. Still here.
阿伦·勒纳还说了什么
Uh, what else did Aaron Lerner say?
他有没有什么有关...  说些其他的
Did he say anything else about... Anything else?
你懂的  和平时一样
Oh, you know, the usual.
"不是我干的
"I didn't do it,
你们抓错人了"
you got the wrong guy."
-他把知道的一切都告诉我了  -一切
- I'm pretty sure he told me everything he knows. - Everything?
一切吗
Everything, huh?
很好
That's good.
是啊
Yeah.
写作顺利
Good luck with the writing.
谢谢
Thanks.
布雷迪警长  我做了什么吗
Chief Brady. What did I do now?
没什么
Nothing.
我只是想告诉你们
Uh, I just wanted to let you know,
我和莱恩警探通过电话了
I talked to detective Ryan.
真的吗  那么  他说了什么
Really? So... What did he say?
他让我们去查查一个当地的毒贩
Well, he got us on to the idea of a local drug dealer.
所以我们找海滩边吸毒男麦克莫瑞谈了谈
So we talked to Mcmurray-- the meth addict from the beach--
他抖出了当地毒品的供应者
And he coughed up the name of the local supplier of meth.
马蒂·本特利
Marty Bentley.
那个码头运营商
The marina operator?
对  但这样说得通
Yeah, but that makes sense.
这样他就知道阿伦·勒纳的安排
I mean, he would know aaron lerner's schedule
知道他什么时候出航
and when he could take the boat out.
没错
Right.
所以我们申请了搜查令去搜查他家
So we got a warrant to search his apartment
找到了给富兰克林发短信叫他去码头的
and found the burner cell phone that sent the text
一次性手机
summoning Franklin to the marina.
很好
Good.
很好  恭喜了
Well, that's great. Congrats.
谢了  如果没有你们和你们在纽约的资源
Thanks. Hey, I couldn't have done it without the two of you
我没法破了这个案子
and your resources in New York.
如果你们能一起去逮捕他  我会很荣幸的
Um... I'd be honored if you came to the arrest.
不去
No.
我们怎么能说不呢
Well, how can we say no?
警察  趴下
Police! Down! Get down!
警察  警察
Police! Police!
布雷迪警长第一次掏枪
So chief Brady's first time pulling his gun.
卡塞尔  也许我该进去
Oh, Castle. Maybe I should go in there.
你没带枪
You don't have a gun.
是啊  不过你也总是不带枪乱闯
Yeah, but that never stops you.
我很幸运
Well, I'm lucky.
我们抓到他了
We got him.
船舱安全了
Cabin secured.
布雷迪警长  干得漂亮
Nice one, chief Brady.
-谢谢你  探长  -不客气
- Thank you, detective. - Yeah.
感觉和你书中的故事一样吧  卡塞尔
Just like out of one of your books, huh, Castle?
对   码头运营商兼职毒贩
Yeah. Uh, marina owner with side meth business
杀死竞争对手
kills competition.
命名《汉普顿希特》  如果我要写的话
Call it "Hamptons Heat," and if I ever write it,
我确定会加入勇敢的布雷迪警长一角
I'll be sure to include a gutsy chief Brady character.
那不是我的
That's not mine.
听着  我告诉你们  我什么也没做
Look, I'm telling you, I didn't do anything.
你们抓错人了
You got the wrong guy.
警长  目前我就找到几袋毒品
Chief, so far I found baggies of meth
和一把点30的卡宾枪
and an automag iii .30 carbine.
这枪是30口径的子弹
Which shoots 30-caliber bullets
和我们在死者身上取出的子弹一致
just like the ones that we pulled out of our victim.
这就是凶器
That's our murder weapon.
我想这样可以结案了  干得好  副警长
Well, I guess that seals it. Good--good work, deputy.
太荒谬了
This is ridiculous.
我没杀人  你们抓错人了
I didn't kill anybody. You got the wrong guy.
是啊  是啊
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
看着脚下
Watch your step.
警官  等一下
Officer, hold on a second there.
怎么了  卡塞尔
What is it, Castle?
这个结
This knot.
这边两个结
Both of these knots.
这是一个完美的八字形结
That's a perfect figure eight with an underhand,
干净利落  这是你系的吗  本特利
neatly flemished. Did you tie these, Bentley?
当然  那是我的船
Of course I did. It's my boat.
你觉得如何  卡塞尔
What about it, Castle?
很漂亮
Well, it's beautiful.
我是说  非常完美
I mean, it's perfect.
教科书一般完美
That knot could be in a book of nautical knots.
这与此案有什么关系
What does that have to do with anything?
大家都认为凶手是
Everyone agrees that the killer is the same person
偷了阿伦·勒纳船的人
Who stole Aaron Lerner's boat.
那个人得把船系在码头
That person had to tie the boat to the dock,
但是那个结系得很马虎
But that knot was sloppy.
我甚至被它绊倒了
I even tripped over it.
无论是谁系了这个八字形
Whoever tied these figure eights
一定是个有经验的船夫
is an experienced boatman.
打结是他们与生俱来的手艺
Tying knots would be their second nature.
他们打不出这么马虎的结
They'd be incapable of tying a sloppy knot.
本特利不可能是凶手
Bentley can't be the killer.
但是我们在本特利的公寓
But we found the burner phone
发现了打给富兰克林的
that placed the call to Franklin
一次性手机
in Bentley's apartment.
你怎么解释
How do you explain that?
很简单  有人陷害
Well, that's easy. It was planted.
就像本特利的船上发现的毒品和枪支
Just like Bentley's boat here had the meth and the gun,
证据定会显示
which I'm sure forensics will show
这就是谋杀时用的凶器
Is thehe actual murder weapon.
那你觉得会是谁要栽赃
And just who do you think planted it?
你来告诉我
Well, you tell me.
布雷迪警长  谁从麦克莫瑞那里
Uh, Chief Brady, who got the information from McMurray
得知本特利的消息
on Bentley?
是琼斯  琼斯副警长
Jones. It was Deputy Jones.
好了  好了  退后
Okay, okay, get back!
大家退后
Everybody stay back!
放轻松  琼斯
Take it easy, Jones.
我们不想让任何人受伤
We don't want anybody to get hurt.
你这个富有的周末狂欢者  你觉得你很聪明
You rich weekenders, you think you're so smart.
与此同时  你污染了我们的海滩
Meantime, you-- you pollute our beaches,
你四处挥霍你的钱  好像你是上等人
You throw your money around like you're better than us.
我从不觉得我是上等人
I don't think I'm better than you.
闭嘴
Oh, shut up.
我从不在乎这些
I didn't care about that.
但是后来富兰克林在城里挣的钱
But then Franklin's city money
对他来说根本不够
wasn't good enough for him.
他不得不染指我的副业
He had to move in on my side business.
所以我做了必须要做的事
So I did what I had to do--
抓到了
Got it.
干得好
Nice!
这可是《汉普顿希特》里我没想到的反转
There's a "Hamptons Heat" twist I did not see coming.
抱歉我们一直怀疑你有嫌疑
Sorry about the whole "Accusing you of murder"--
还是朋友吧
Still buddies?
是
Yeah.
结果发现是琼斯
So it turns out that Jones
付给麦克莫瑞五百块
paid McMurray 500 bucks
去抹黑本特利
to point a finger at Bentley.
五百块去毁了一个人的一生
Wow. $500 to ruin a man's life, huh?
不是危言耸听
And not to sound all scooby,
但如果不是你  他很有可能逃脱了  卡塞尔
but he might have gotten away with it if not for you, Castle.
能帮到我在执法部门的朋友
Well, I'm always glad to help out
我一向乐意
my friends in law enforcement.
说到这里
Speaking of which,
我想来段祝酒辞
I would like to make a toast.
布雷迪警长
Chief Brady,
不是所有人都能像你一样应付得了
Not everyone could've handled themselves
今天在码头上遇到的状况
the way you did on the dock today.
你是个好警察
You're a good cop.
-布雷迪警长  -敬你
- Chief Brady. - Here's to you.
谢谢你  贝克特警探
Thank you, Detective Beckett.
你放心  我会保守秘密的
And you can rest assured, your secret is safe with me.
谢谢
Thank you.
Yeah, thank you.
我枪击了嫌犯
I shot the bad guy.
是啊
You did.
没错
Yeah, you did.
厉害
Nice.
是啊
Yeah.
我该走了
I should go.
-好的  -别啊
Oh, of course. Oh, no.
找新的副警长  我
Find a new deputy. I--
是啊
Yeah, you do.
很高兴认识你
It was so great to meet you.
我也是
You too.
是啊
Yeah.
-拜  -拜
- Bye. - Bye.
走
Let's go.
请
Please.
汉普顿的案子是解决了
Well, the case in the hamptons has been solved,
但是神秘男友事件
but the case of the secret boyfriend
还没有解决
remains open.
贝克特的联调局前男友
Turns out Beckett's FBI ex
已被调到欧洲六个月了
has been stationed in europe for six months.
怎么
What?
你查到了吗
You got anything?
没
Nah.
我只是在想  我们还是别查了
No, I was just thinking, maybe we should drop it.
别管贝克特的私生活了
You know, let Beckett's private life stay private.
你是说放弃吗
What, you mean give up?
真正的警探可不会放弃一个案子的
A real detective never gives up on a case, bro.
这不是真正的案子
You know it's not a real case, right?
怎么  你知道啥叫真正的案子啊
You're gonna tell me what a real case is?
据我所知  有凶案才算
Uh, last time I checked, it's when there was a murder.
凶案倒是有
Oh, there's been a murder all right.
死的是你的精神
Your spirit.
-擦  -还有你的尊严
- Wow. - Yeah. Your dignity, too.
你知道吗
Huh. Well, you know what?
冲你这句话  第一轮酒你请
Just for that, the first round's on you.
想得美  拜拜布鲁斯
Yeah, good luck with that. Bruce.
拜拜布鲁斯
Bruce.
说来有趣
You know what's funny?
我的借口是到这里写书
My cover was that I was coming out here to write,
我还真找到了点子
and I actually got an idea for a book.
《汉普顿希特》
Oh. "Hamptons Heat."
你是认真的
So you're serious about that, huh?
故事都有了  那是最难的部分
Well, I already have the story. That's the hardest part.
有结尾了吗
So do you have an ending yet?
那个嘛
Oh, well,
有些点子
I had some ideas,
但是我接受各种建议
but, uh, I'm open to suggestions.
这个怎么样
How about this?
这个周末跟希特探长
The weekend hadn't turned out
想象得完全不一样
exactly as detective heat had imagined,
但是
but now nothing...
即便是海滩再发生谋杀案
not even another murder on the beach
也无法阻止她得到她想要的
could stop her from getting exactly what she desired...
东西
most.
这个好
Oh, that's good.
作者一栏得署我名字
Can I get a writer's credit?
-好说  -好吧
- We'll talk. - Okay.